Normand Chartier Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Normand Chartier Papers.
ca. 1974-1992.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Chartier, Normand, 1945-.
4 linear feet.
Author and illustrator of more than forty children's books. Owner of Chartier Gallery in Brooklyn, CT.
MSS19930070
Biography
Author and illustrator of more than forty children's books. Owner of Chartier Gallery in Brooklyn, CT.
Scope and Content
The collection contains artwork, notes, correspondence, photographs and other materials pertaining to Normand Chartier's illustrations of several children's books.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk. Illustrations of the work of Marjorie Sharmat can also be found in the Marc Simont Papers.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Children's literature, American—20th century.; Children's literature—Connecticut illustrators.; Children's literature—Connecticut authors.; Children's literature, American—Illustrations.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Books.; Manuscripts.; Publications.; Photographs.; Audio visual materials.
Occupations:
Artist.; Illustrator.; Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Materials transferred in two installments, 1992 and 1993. All but two sketches (bear and rabbit and Griselda) are on deposit.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Books, ca. 1974-1992
  - Bartholomew the Bossy by Marjorie Weinman Sharmat (Box 2)
  - Macmillan, 1984.
    - Pp. 10-11, (1 item) (Box OS)
    - Pencil sketches, (11 items) (Box 2)
    - Text, (8 items)
    - Dummy
    - Reference materials, art, photographs, (34 items)
    - Photocopies of dummies and sketches, (107 items)
    - Galley pieces, (6 items)
    - Postcard, (1 item)
  - Boris the Boring Bear by Ellen Jackson. (Box 2)
  - Macmillan, 1992.
    - Sketches and partial watercolors, (12 items)
    - Text with pencil sketches, (6 items)
    - Correspondence, (3 items)
    - Layout specifications, (2 items)
    - Dummy with original art, (19 items)
    - Galley with pencil sketches, (5 items)
    - Proofs folded and gathered
    - Sketches
      - Bear and Rabbit drawing at easel
      - “ 'Well, I borrowed it from somebody,' said Griselda”
  - Devin and Goliath by Mary Blount Christian. (Box 1)
  - Addison-Wesley, 1974.
    - Cover, pp. 1-32, (17 items)
  - Griselda's New Year by Marjorie Weinman Sharmat. (Box 2)
  - Macmillan, 1979.
    - Color Proofs, (12 items)
    - Dummy with pen and ink sketches, (30 items)
    - Original art with overlay, (2 items)
  - Pack 109 by Mike Thaler. (Box 2)
  - Dutton, 1988.
    - Pencil sketches, (21 items)
    - Water colors, (2 items)
    - Correspondence, (1 item)
  - Silly Fred by Karen Wagner. (Box 2)
  - Picadilly Press, 1990.
    - Dummy with original art and one watercolor, (17 items)
    - Galley, (3 items)
    - Pencil sketches, (3 items)
    - Photocopies of sketches, (3 items)
    - Correspondence, 1988; (6 items)